bikewale.com 2019-05-21

# Privacy Policy - BikeWale

Privacy of your personal information is very important to us. We do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more about the ways in which we use and protect your personal information. The privacy practices of this statement apply to our services available under the domain and sub-domains of [ www.bikewale.com ](https://www.bikewale.com/) ( ["bikewale.com"](https://bikewale.com/) or "Site") and apply generally to our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries or joint venture websites whose specific privacy policies are available from our Privacy Central pages. By visiting this Site you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree please do not use or access our Site. 

This Privacy Policy describes the information, as part of the normal operation of our services, we collect from you and what may happen to that information. Although this policy may seem long, we have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about BikeWale.com’s practices so that you can make informed decisions. By accepting the Privacy Policy and the User Agreement in registration, you expressly consent to (i) be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and User Agreement; and (ii) our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the User Agreement. 

1\. Your Privacy - Our Commitment 

At BikeWale.com, we are extremely proud of our commitment to protect your privacy and the personal information you disclose on the Site. We value your trust in us. We will work hard to earn your confidence so that you can enthusiastically use our services and recommend us to friends and family. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our Site. 

2\. BikeWale.com Privacy Guarantee 

BikeWale.com promises that we will not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. From time to time we may reveal general statistical information about our Site and visitors, such as number of visitors, number and type of goods and services purchased, etc. Your trust and confidence are our highest priority. 

3\. Information we collect 

When you use our Site, we collect and store your personal information provided by you. Our primary goal in doing so is to provide a safe, efficient, smooth and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our Site to make your experience safer and easier. Importantly, we only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose. In general, you can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Once you give us your personal information, you are not anonymous to us. To fully use our Site, you will need to register using our online registration form, where you may be required to provide us with your contact and identity information and other personal information as indicated on the forms throughout the Site. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature on the Site.   
We may automatically track certain information about you based upon your behavior on our Site. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve our users. This information is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our Site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our Site or not), your computer browser information, and your IP address.  
We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the Site to help analyze our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide information that is targeted to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Site and you may be required to reenter your password more frequently during a session.  

BikeWale serves all its advertisements using Google's Doubeclick ad serving platform. You may opt-out of the advertising-related data collection [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) (choose Google from the list).

If you choose to buy or sell bikes using the Site then we collect information about your buying and selling behavior. We also collect other users' comments about you in our feedback area. If you choose to post messages on our forum or leave feedback for other users, we will collect that information. We retain this information as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law. If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. 

4\. Our use of your information 

We use your personal information to facilitate the services you request. We use your personal information and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site to: resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote safe trading; collect fees owed; measure consumer interest in the services provided by us, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our User Agreement; sharing in the course of Classified listings with prospective buyers/sellers(including dealers involved in buying and selling) as the case may be; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular we may examine your personal information to identify users using multiple User IDs or aliases. We may compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions and for accuracy. If you choose to list a bike for sale on the Site we use your address and billing information to bill you and provide associated support.  
You agree that we may use your personal information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Site usage, improve the Site's content and product offerings, and customize the Site's content, layout, and services. These uses improve the Site and better tailor it to meet your needs, so as to provide you with a smooth, efficient, safe and customized experience while using the Site. You agree that we may use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Site. By accepting the User Agreement and Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to opt out of the receipt of certain communications in your profile. You may make changes to your profile at any time. 

5\. Our disclosure of your information 

We may also use your information to deliver information to you that, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as new services and promotions. The following are examples of some categories of persons to whom we would share your information with from time-to-time. 

1\. Advertisements

> a. Where a user enters information on any form of an advertiser, the information is simultaneously collected by BikeWale.com and the advertiser. The information is used by BikeWale.com in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and is used by the advertiser as per the advertisers prevalent privacy policies. Because we do not control the privacy practices of these advertisers, you should evaluate their practices before deciding to provide the said information.Moreover, you are authorizing BikeWale.com, its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, partners and joint ventures, who are accessing your information by virtue of their association with BikeWale.com to communicate with you through telephone/mobile, e-mail, SMS or other modes of communication even if your number(s) is/are registered in the National Do Not Call Registry (NDNC) or www.nccptrai.gov.in 
> 
> b. BikeWale.com may also aggregate (gather up data across all user accounts) personally identifiable information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for other marketing and promotional purposes. 

2\. Classifieds Listings

> a. When a user lists a classifieds advertisement, and the advertisement receives an expression of interest by the interested user, the interested user will be provided the contact information of the user listing the advertisement as provided in that user's registration form. 
> 
> b. When a user expresses an interest in a classifieds advertisement, the user who has listed the advertisement will be provided the contact information of the interested user as provided in the interested user's registration form. 

3\. Bikes and Services offered on the Site are by third parties  
There are certain bikes and services for which third parties request for information before the service is listed on the Site (example: application for bike loan). The information provided by the user for such purposes is simultaneously collected by BikeWale.com and the respective third party. This information is utilised by the third party in accordance with its privacy policy and the terms of the offer. Because we do not control the privacy practices of these third parties, you should evaluate their practices before deciding to use their services. 

4\. Internal Service Providers   
We may use third parties that we refer to as internal service providers to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of the business, product and service operations that we provide to you on the Site (e.g., search technology, discussion boards, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs) and therefore we may provide some of your personal information directly to these internal service providers. These internal service providers' are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information we provide them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced Site related operation, unless you have explicitly agreed or given your prior permission to them for additional uses. In some instances, the internal service provider may collect information directly from you (such as for Site surveys). In these cases, you will be notified of the involvement of the internal service provider, and all additional information you provide them and their additional uses will be strictly up to you. If you provide additional information to an internal service provider directly, then their use of your personal information is governed by their applicable privacy policy. 

5\. Other Corporate Entities   
We share much of our data, including personal information about you, with our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures that are committed to serving your online trading needs and related services, throughout the world. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. Our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this document, to the extent allowed by applicable law. BikeWale.com, its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, its joint ventures, or any combination of such, will share some or all of your personal information with another business entity should we plan to, merge with, or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information.Moreover, you are authorizing BikeWale.com, its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, partners and joint ventures, who are accessing your information by virtue of their association with BikeWale.com to communicate with you through telephone/mobile, e-mail, SMS or other modes of communication even if your number(s) is/are registered in the National Do Not Call Registry (NDNC) or www.nccptrai.gov.in 

6\. Legal Requests   
We cooperate with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights fraud and other rights, to help protect you and the community from bad actors. Therefore, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, city, state, telephone number, email address, User ID history, fraud complaints, and bike listing history without a subpoena or summon. Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy and our ability to keep the community free from bad actors, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other government officials without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or report suspected illegal activity. Further, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, email, and company name to intellectual property rights owners under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity.   
Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. 

6A. Your Obligations 

You agree, undertake and confirm that while providing your information on the Site you will not host, display, upload, modify, publish, transmit, update or share any information that:- 

> (a) belongs to another person and to which you do not have any right to; 
> 
> (b) is grossly harmful, harassing, blasphemous, defamatory, obscene, pornographic, pedophilic, libelous, invasive of another privacy hateful, or racially, ethnically objectionable, disparaging, relating or encouraging money laundering or gambling, or otherwise unlawful in any manner whatever; 
> 
> (c) harm minor in any way; 
> 
> (d) infringes any patent, trademark, copyright or other proprietary rights; 
> 
> (e) violates any law for the time being in force; 
> 
> (f) deceives or misleads the Site and or existing and new users about the origin of such messages or communicates any information which is grossly offensive or menacing in nature; 
> 
> (g) impersonate any other person; 
> 
> (h) contains software viruses or any other computer code, files or programs designed to interrupt, destroy or limit the functionality of any computer resource; or 
> 
> (i) threatens the unity, integrity, defence, security or sovereignty of India, friendly relations with foreign states, or public order or causes incitement to the commission of any cognizable offence or prevents investigation of any offence or is insulting any other nation. 

6B. Your use of other users' information 

In order to facilitate interaction among all BikeWale.com community members, our Site allows you to access other users' contact information. Further, as a seller you will be sent via email the personal details like email, address and other information of the buyer(s), and as a buyer you will be sent via email the personal details like email, address and other information of the seller(s). By entering into our User Agreement, you agree that, with respect to other user's personally identifiable information that you obtain through the Site or through a BikeWale.com related communication or BikeWale.com facilitated transaction, BikeWale.com hereby grants to you a license to use such information only for: 

> (a) BikeWale.com related communications that are not unsolicited commercial messages,
> 
> (b) using co-branded services offered through BikeWale.com, and
> 
> (c) any other purpose that such user expressly opts into after adequate disclosure of the purpose(s).In all cases, you must give users an opportunity to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them

In addition, under no circumstances, except as defined in this Section, can you disclose personally identifiable information about another user to any third party without our consent and the consent of such other user after adequate disclosure. 

BikeWale.com and our users do not tolerate spam. Therefore, without limiting the foregoing, you are not licensed to add a BikeWale.com user-even a user who has purchased a bike from you-to your mail list (email or physical mail) without their express consent after adequate disclosure. 

7\. Access or change your personally identifiable information 

To protect your privacy and security, we will verify your identity before granting access or making changes to your personally-identifying information. If you have registered your profile on BikeWale.com, your BikeWale.com ID and Password are required in order to access your profile information. 

8\. Your consent 

By using the Site, you consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on the Site by BikeWale.com. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes in this document available on the Site so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will be communicated through our Site at least 10 days in advance of implementation. You may also note that you may at anytime, in writing to us, withdraw your consent to use your information in which case BikeWale.com will desist from using it anymore. However, please note that BikeWale.com reserves the right to discontinue all services in the event you withdraw your consent.
